<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stable Diffusion | Devin Murphy</title><link>https://example.com/tag/stable-diffusion/</link><atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/stable-diffusion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Stable Diffusion</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://example.com/media/icon_hua6395a99da531b2e70e32e5401dc9674_120945_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Stable Diffusion</title><link>https://example.com/tag/stable-diffusion/</link></image><item><title>CalPal</title><link>https://example.com/project/calpal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://example.com/project/calpal/</guid><description>&lt;p>Mobile calendaring platforms provide unparalleled convenience and accessibility, yet often lack the tactile engagement and personalized touch of physical mediums. This paper introduces CalPal, an innovative multimodal digital wall calendar designed to bridge this gap by blending digital convenience with the benefits of traditional calendars. CalPal integrates pen-based event tracking, seamless synchronization with Google Calendar, intuitive gesture-based navigation, and dynamic theming based on monthly events, distinguishing it from existing digital wall calendar solutions. Our system on average is able to detect the navigation gestures (flipping forward and flipping backward) with 98% and 87% accuracy respectively. Through a comprehensive user study, we also demonstrate user satisfaction with CalPal&amp;rsquo;s intuitive interaction modalities and custom theming. Overall, these results indicate that CalPal represents a promising approach to harmonizing the strengths of digital and traditional calendaring practices, thereby providing users with a more holistic and insightful scheduling tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="system-demo">System Demo&lt;/h2>
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TuvQ1oiRmB8?si=tLA5axvZc4PYfjer" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;h2 id="project-report">Project Report&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning more, lots of the details are available in our project report writeup linked above!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>